A Guide to the Records of the Office of the Vice President for Administration, Stuart K. Cassell, 1945-1975
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Office of the Vice President for Administration, Stuart K. Cassell, 1945-1975
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 6/1/1
68.4 Cubic Feet; 69 boxes
This collection consists primarily of correspondence with Stuart K. Cassell, first Vice President for Administration (1966-1975). There is a large amount of material concerning budget and other financial matters, as well as construction, buildings and grounds maintenance, and other physical plant matters. The collection also contains Cassell's records as Business Manager, 1945-1966. Because the bulk of the material concerns Cassell's position as Vice President for Administration, but the material is interfiled, the records have been kept together as one collection under RG 6/1/1.
Cassell, Stuart K., 1910-1976
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the Office of the Vice President for Administration, Stuart K. Cassell were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in November 1990.
Biographical Note
A native of Rural Retreat, Virginia, Stuart Kent Cassell, Jr. (1910-1976) first came to Virginia Tech in the late 1920s as an undergraduate, receiving a bachelor's degree in animal science in 1932 and a master's in economics in 1933. He became an instructor of agricultural economics in 1933, and in 1939 he was appointed state executive officer for the Agricultural Adjustment Administration. Appointed finance and business manager in 1945, he was an administrator under four presidents. He was instrumental in the planning and long-term development of Virginia Tech to accommodate its steadily increasing enrollment. He was also a member of the board of directors of VPI Facilities, Inc. and the Virginia Tech Student Aid Association. He was named vice president for administration by President T. Marshall Hahn, Jr. in 1966. He died in October 1976 at the age of 66. The Stuart K. Cassell Coliseum was named in his honor and dedicated on September 17, 1977.
Scope and Content
The records of the Vice President for Administration, Stuart K. Cassell span the years 1945 to 1975. The records consist primarily of Cassell's correspondence, first as business manager (1945-1966) and then as vice president for administration (1966-1975). The records concern budgets and other financial matters as well as construction, buildings and grounds maintenance, and other physical plant matters.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by year. Within each year, materials are arranged by subject file.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Office of the Vice President for Administration, Stuart K. Cassell by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
University Archives; University History
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
People:
Cassell, Stuart K., 1910-1976
Contents List
- 1945
  - A Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbitt, J.R. – Director, Buildings and Grounds, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aeronautics – Department Statement of Expenses and Income for Quarter Ending March 31, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aeronautics – Herbert D. Tinker, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aeronautics – William A. Mehl, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agreements, VPI & Other Parties, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Airport Applicants (2 folders), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Airport Matters, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allotments from Richmond, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Applications for Faculty Apartment and Dining Hall Position, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Barringer, J.M. – Civilian Students, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bennett, J. Gordon – Auditor, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bid for Surplus Property at Mason & Hanger Company, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Blanket Letters, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brown, R.M. – Library, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Buck, Dr. J.L. Blair – Conference: College Offerings, 1945-08-22-1945-08-29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget Matters, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Building Committee, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Buildings & Grounds, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Building Stone, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bulletins – Surplus Government Property (2 folders), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Committee Work on Faculty Personnel Policy, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Community Federation, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cowgill, C.H. – Professor, Architecture, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Culm Coal, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - D Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Day, Jr., S.C. – Assistant Comptroller, Finance Building, Richmond, Virginia, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Departments – Letters Concerning Revision of Classification of Expenditures, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dining Hall Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - E Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Electric Service Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Executive Bulletins, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - F Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Faculty Dining Hall, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Faculty Meetings – Minutes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Frozen Food Locker Project, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Furr, G.L. – Appalachian Electric Power Company, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - G Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Gathright, A.B. – Director, Division of Purchase and Printing, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - H Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Holbrook, J.C. – Chief, Vocational Rehabilitation & Education Division, Veterans Administration, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Hospital, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Hutcheson, Dr. John R. - President, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - [Folder removed from collection] (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - J Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - K Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - L Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Laundry Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - M Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Mc Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Miles, C.P. – Dean of the College, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Norris, E.B. – Dean of Engineering, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - O Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - P Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Permits for Driving Automobiles or Motorcycles, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Perpetual Inventory, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Personal, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Plumbing Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Policy Statement for Allotting College-Owned Campus Houses and Apartments, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Power Sales Agreement, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Printing Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - R Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Requisitions & Orders, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Requisitions – Well Drilling, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Royer, R. Stuart – Consulting Engineer, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - S Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Sanders, Professor H.W. – FFA Convention, 1945-09-27-1945-09-29 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Saunders, Fred Q. – Chief Engineer, Division of the Budget, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Summer Activities, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Surplus Government Property Correspondence and Orders, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - T Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tailor Shop, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Trailers for Married Veterans, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's Office, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - V Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Veteran's Educational Advisers Conference – Mr. F.O. Wygal, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - W Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - War Bond Drive, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - War Fund Campaign, 1945-10 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Water Supply and Storage, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Wells – Drilling & Testing, Invitation to Bid, etc., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wells – Furnishing & Installing Pumps, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Wiley & Wilson, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Wine, W.E., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - XYZ Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 1946
  - Abbitt, J.R. – Director, Buildings and Grounds, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Administrative Council, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Airport Matters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Alfred Hopkins & Associates, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bennett, J. Gordon – Auditor of Public Accounts, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Blanket Letters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bradford, J.H. – Director of Budget, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brown, Ralph M. – Library, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Budget Matters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Building Committee, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Building Program – Agricultural Units 3, 4, 5, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Capital Outlay Items Approved for Purchase (208-50), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Carneal & Johnston – Miscellaneous Letters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Civilian Production Administration, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cowgill, C.H. – Professor, Architecture, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cregger, S.G. – Auditor, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Day, Jr., S.C. – Assistant Comptroller, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Derring, Paul N. – YMCA, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Dining Hall Department, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dining Hall Letters – RE: Position of Manager (2 folders), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - E Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Electric Service Department, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Executive Bulletins, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Farrier, Dr. Paul – Director of Admissions, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Federal Public Housing Authority – Concerning Dormitory Facilities etc. in Connection with Radford, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Federal Public Housing Authority – Trailers (2 folders), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Fogleman, J.B. – Treasurer, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fuqua, R.W. – Bookstore, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Homecoming, 1946-10-26 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hudgins, M.S. – Pumping Station and Outfall Sewer, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hutcheson, Dr. John R. – President, Folder 1 of 2, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hutcheson, Dr. John R. – President, Folder 2 of 2, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hutcheson, T.B. – Dean of Agriculture, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - I Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Infirmary, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Inspection Reports – Sanitary, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Insurance – Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - J Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - K Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - L Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Laundry Department, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lunsford – Insurance, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mc Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - McCay, M.S. – Professor, Physics, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - McGauhey, P.H. – Professor, Sanitary Engineering, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - McNeil, R.H. – Director of Public Relations, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Meal Rates, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Military Department, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Motor Vehicles Division, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Murray, D.R. – IBM, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Newman, Dr. Walter S. – Vice President, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Office of Price Administration, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Personal, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Roop, Redmond I. – Attorney, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - S Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Saunders, Fred Q. – Chief Engineer, Division of the Budget, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Sewage Disposal System – Pumping Station and Outfall Sewer For Sewage Treatment Works (3 folders), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 35-37)
  - Sewage Project – Bids on Sewage Disposal Plant, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Student Finance Board, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Student Organizations, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Trailer Camp #1 – Construction, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Trailer & Other Housing Advertisements, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Veterans Administration (2 folders), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
  - World War II Memorial Committee, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - World War II Memorial Service, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- 1947
  - Building Program – Temporary Building, Main Campus, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Financial Report on Audit for the Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- 1948
  - Abbitt, J.R. – Director, Buildings and Grounds, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Administrative Council, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Admissions, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Aetna Insurance Company, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Allotment – Advice, etc., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Allotments from Richmond, Requests, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Alumni Association, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bennett, J. Gordon – Auditor of Public Accounts, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boiler Reports, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Boiler Water Treatment Equipment Bids (3 folders), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
  - Bradford, J.H – Director of the Budget, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Budget Matters, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Building Committee, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Capital Outlay Items – Approved, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Capital Outlay Items – Approved, July 27, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Carneal & Johnston, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carneal & Johnston – Dormitory Project (2 folders), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Chas. Lunsford Sons and Izard Insurance, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Clyborn & Massie – Merrimac Culm Coal, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Coleman, W.H. – Chief Educational Officer, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Commencement, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cooper, B.N. – Head of Geology Department, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cowgill, C.H. – Head of Architecture Department, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Danville Extension, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dekker, Henry J. – Treasurer, V.P.I., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Division of Accounts and Purchases Virginia State, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dormitories, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dormitories – Bids, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Engineering Week Committee, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Executive Bulletins, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Farrier, P.H. – Director of Admissions, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hanson, A.R. – Public Housing Administration, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Heath, Dr. Fred C. – Health Officer, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Homecoming Day, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hummel, R.S. – District Engineer, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Hutcheson, John R. – Chancellor, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Inspection Reports, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Johnson, Jr., C.P. – Assistant Auditor of Public Accounts (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Judge Brockenbrough Lamb, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Litton, G.W. – Animal Husbandry Department, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - M Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Mall, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Mc Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - McCann, Lieutenant Colonel James H., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - McGauhey, P.H. – Professor, Sanitary Engineering, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Miles, C.P. – Dean of the College, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Miller, W.H. – Director of Dining Halls, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Minter, S.R. – Manager, V.P.I. Electric Service, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Morris, A.V. – Chairman, Registration Committee, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Mosby, H.S. – Director, Virginia Cooperative Wildlife Station, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Munford, T.W. – Colonel, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Murray, D.R. – IBM, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Murray, W.A. – Head, Department of Electrical Engineering, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Newman, Walter S. – President, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - News Releases, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Norris, E.B. – Dean of Engineering, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Norton, Paul T. – Professor, Industrial Engineering, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - O Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Overholser, E.L. – Head, Horticulture Department, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - P Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Personal, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Personnel Data, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Poteet, G.F. – Surplus Property, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Power House Addition – Bids, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Power Plant Addition (2 folders), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 65-66)
  - Power Plant – Boiler Feed Pumping Unit (3 folders), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Power Plant – Structural Steel Work, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - R Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Radford Project, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Radio Station WUVT, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Redd, H.B. – Alumni Secretary, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Requisitions & Orders, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Requisitions – Travel, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Richardson, Webster – Professor, Physics, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Robb, Seymour – Library, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Robeson, F.L. – Head, Physics Department, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - S Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sanders, H.W. – Head, Vocational Education, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Saunders, Fred Q. – Chief Engineer, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Scherer, Philip C. – Professor, Physical Chemistry, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Scholarship Committee for Athletes, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Scholarships, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sewage Plant, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Shanks, F.O. – V.P.I. Printing Department, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Slusher, Clarice – Registrar, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - State Soil Conservation Committee, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Statements – Financial, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Student Employees – Student Assistants, Counselors, Waiters, etc., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Student Fees – Individuals, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Student Life Committee, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Student Unions, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Students – Graduate Fees, etc., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Sullivan, H.J. – Temporary Buildings, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Summer Conferences, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Surplus Equipment, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Surplus Property – Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
  - Swink, H.W. – Personnel Officer, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - T Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Tate, Mildred T. – Head, Home Economics Department, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Telephone Charges, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Thurman and Boone Company, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Traffic Regulations, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Trailer Camps, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Transcripts & Photostats – Procedure for Handling Charges, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Turner, J.M. – Power House Addition, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - V Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - V.P.I. Research Foundation, Inc., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Vandenberg, H.P.C. – Planning Engineer, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Vending Machines on Campus, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Veterans Administration, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Vilbrandt, F.C. – Head, Chemical Engineering, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Virginia Tuition Privilege, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - W Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Watson, J.W. – Head of Chemistry Departments (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Whittemore, J.W. – Associate Dean of Engineering, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Wilson, I.D. – Head, Department of Biology, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Wine, W.E., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Woolwine, C.R. – Health Officer, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Young, H.N. – Director, Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Younger, W.L. – V.P.I. Athletic Association, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 59)
- 1949
  - A Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Abbitt, J.R. – Director, Buildings & Grounds, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Accounts & Purchases, Division of, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Administrative Council, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Admissions, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Advisory Committee on S.A.B., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Agricultural Units #3, #4 & #5, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Agricultural Units – Bids, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Alfred Hopkins & Associates, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Allotment – Advice, etc., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Allotments From Richmond – Requests, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Athletic Association, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bates, R.E. – Director of Student Affairs, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Begg, R.B.H. – Head of Civil Engineering Department, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bennett, J. Gordon – Auditor of Public Accounts, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [Folder removed from collection] (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Blanket Letters, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bradford, J.H. – Director of the Budget, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Broce, Fred – Manager, V.P.I. Airport, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - [Folder removed from collection] (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Budget – 1950-52, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - [Folder removed from collection] (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Building Committee, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Carneal & Johnston, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Carneal & Johnston, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Cato, W.H. – Director, Guidance & Placement1, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Scope and Content
    1Previously labeled Dunlevey, David B. – Director, Guidance & Placement. Mr. Dunlevey resigned from his position in 1949 and no files relating to his employment are located within the file.
  - Civilian Student Regulations Committee, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Clyborne & Massie – Merrimac Culm Coal, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - College & University Personnel Association, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Committee on Commencement, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Connecting Steam Lines Project, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Cregger, S.G. – Auditor (2 folders), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
  - D Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Danville Extension (2 folders), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
  - Dekker, Henry J. – Treasurer, V.P.I., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dormitory Supervisor, Custodian, Students – Rules and Regulations - Duties, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - E Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - F Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Financial Report on Audit for the Fiscal Year ended June 30, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - G Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - H Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Holland, VA – Main Hog Building at Holland Experiment Station, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Housing Data, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Hummel, R.S. – Federal Works Agency, Bureau of Community Facilities, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Hutcheson, T.B. – Dean of Agriculture, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Inaugural Committee, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - K Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - L Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - M Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Monthly Statement of Revenues Other than from Appropriations, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Newman, W.S. – President, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Norris, E.B. – Dean of Engineering, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - O Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - P Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Personnel Data, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 52)